parinc.com 2017-06-06

# PAR - Psychological Assessment Resources, Inc. - Privacy Policy

Last Updated: August 1, 2016

PAR, Inc. ("PAR") is committed to protecting your privacy. We developed this Privacy Policy to share with you our information collection practices and the options you have when visiting [www.parinc.com](http://www.parinc.com/) (hereinafter referred to as "the Web site" or "the Site"). This Privacy Policy is an online Privacy Policy and applies only to information collected from you through this Web site. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information that you furnish to us offline or in any other manner except through this Web site.

Please note that other Web sites affiliated with PAR may be governed by separate policies. When visiting any of our other sites, please refer to its Privacy Policy.

By using this Site, you are agreeing to accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

PAR occasionally may update this Privacy Policy. When we do, we will revise the "updated" date at the top of the Privacy Policy. In the event that we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you at our option either by placing a prominent notice on the home page of our Web site or by sending you a notification directly. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically to stay fully informed about how we are protecting your personal information. Be advised that your continued use of this Web site constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any updates.

As referenced throughout this Privacy Policy, the term "Personally Identifiable Information" means any piece of information that potentially can be used to uniquely identify, contact, or locate a single person and that PAR collects from you. Personally Identifiable Information may include, without limitation, information such as user name, password, first name, last name, address, e-mail address, phone number, credit card number, audio or video in which you are depicted or identifiable, etc.

PAR employs commercially reasonable efforts to protect Personally Identifiable Information from loss, misuse, and other unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction.

## Who Is Collecting Your Information

PAR is the sole owner of the information collected; except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, we will not sell, share, rent, or loan this information to any third party. However, we may use and share aggregated information that does not personally identify you with third parties in order to improve the Site for our Web site users. You can always be assured the information we collect is used to provide a more personalized experience for our Web site users.

None of the required information and/or optional information collected on any form on this Web site is used for other purposes than those stated on such form or in this Privacy Policy; however, as discussed below in more detail, PAR may share information provided through the Web site with third parties under contract with PAR to assist in providing certain services or other features offered to our Web site users. In the event that PAR utilizes a third party to provide such services, our contract with the third party will include obligations on the third party to keep all information obtained during such contract confidential and secure.

## Using Information About You

PAR respects your privacy. The information you provide will never be rented or sold. PAR will use the contact information you provide for internal purposes, such as confirming and tracking your order; subscription or registration; analyzing preferences, trends, and statistics; and informing you of our new products, services, and offers. We also may disclose information to outside companies that help us bring you the products and services we offer. For example, we may work with an outside company to (a) manage our database of customer information, (b) assist us in distributing e-mails, (c) assist us with direct marketing and data collection, (d) provide storage and analysis, (d) provide fraud prevention, and (e) perform other services designed to assist us in maximizing our business potential. We require that these outside companies agree to keep confidential all information we share with them and to use the information only to perform duties specified in our agreements with them.

If you prefer not to have your information shared with these organizations, please contact us by telephone at 1.800.331.8378, by e-mail at [custsup@parinc.com](mailto:custsup@parinc.com), or by written notice to PAR, Inc., 16204 N. Florida Ave., Lutz, FL 33549.

If you would like to opt out of PAR direct mail advertising, please send your complete name and address indicating your desire to opt out to PAR, 16204 N. Florida Ave., Lutz, FL 33549.

## Children Under Age 13 Years

PAR does not target children under the age of 13 years and does not offer or knowingly sell any of its products or services to children. PAR does not knowingly collect any personal information about children under the age of 13 years.

The following are categories of pages on the Web site where we collect Personally Identifiable Information about you.

## What Is Collected, and How Do We Use It

Although you may browse the public pages of our Web site without registering or providing any Personally Identifiable Information, certain sections of our Site do include forms on which you may choose to supply personalized information that will enable you to make purchases online or receive individualized services or features that we cannot offer anonymous users, and certain other pages of our Web site can be accessed only by registered users. You can always choose not to provide information; however, if you do choose not to provide such information, you may not be able to make purchases via the Site or take advantage of certain other Web site features.

Except as necessary to facilitate or fulfill any aspect of any services, products, or features that you purchase or request or register for via the Web site, or as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy, we will not intentionally sell, rent, lease, share, or exchange your Personally Identifiable Information with any third party.

In order to access pages requiring registration, you will be required to create a User Account by completing the registration form and creating a User ID and password (collectively referred to as "Credentials"). If you create a User Account, PAR collects certain Personally Identifiable Information when you register, including your user name, password, first name, last name, and e-mail address.

### Alerts/Catalogs

Our Web site may offer features that allow you to request and receive catalogs or electronic alerts or notices about updates to our Web site, promotional announcements, new products, and other information. When you sign up to receive catalogs or electronic alerts or notices, we will collect certain Personally Identifiable Information, which may include, without limitation, your name, e-mail address, and other basic contact information.

### Newsletters and Other Subscriptions

Various pages on our Web site may include forms that permit you to subscribe to newsletters or other subscriptions. When you register to receive newsletters or other subscriptions, we will collect certain Personally Identifiable Information, which may, include without, limitation your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, and other basic contact information.

### Online Orders

If you order products through our Web site, we will collect Personally Identifiable Information, which may include, without limitation, the name, address, phone number, e-mail address, and shipping and other contact information for the recipient of the item (if different than yours), your name and account number (if applicable) as well as payment information, such as credit card number, billing address, expiration date, and other billing information.

### Surveys and Other Voluntary Demographic Information

In addition to the above information, certain forms on various pages throughout our Site may ask users to voluntarily provide a limited amount of demographic information. In addition, PAR or its affiliates may conduct online surveys that ask you for demographic data, such as your zip code, age, or product use. PAR or PAR's agents may also contact you by e-mail, using the e-mail address collected when you filled out one of the forms on our Web site, with the option to participate in consumer research studies.

Providing such demographic information and participating in such surveys or other consumer research are always voluntary. PAR aggregates the responses we receive before using the information to improve the products and services we offer. We do not link your individual responses to your personal information at any time. PAR uses this information only for internal marketing research to help us better serve our users and customers.

### Contests, Sweepstakes, & Games

From time to time, PAR offers sweepstakes, contests, or other games. If you participate in such promotions, PAR may ask for some personal information, such as names, phone numbers, e-mail addresses, or other contact information, so that we can contact potential contest or sweepstakes winners. We will clearly post the rules and terms of each contest or sweepstakes. From time to time, PAR may retain third party vendors to administer such sweepstakes, games, or contests and, in such circumstances, those third parties will be required to collect your personal information in order to administer and fulfill the promotion as well as to contact potential winners. Please review the Official Rules or Terms and Conditions for such promotions carefully, as the personal information collected during these promotions may be subject to the privacy policies of these third party vendors as well as this Privacy Policy. In that event, the Official Rules or Terms and Conditions will refer you to the privacy policy of the third party vendors. Please review those privacy policies as well, because PAR does not have control over the treatment of personal information by such third party vendors.

### Marketing, Promotional, or Other Transactional Communications

If you have opted to receive marketing, promotional, or other informational communications from or on behalf of PAR, we may use your e-mail address from time to time to contact you to announce new features, products, or services that may be available on our Web site or to send news and information regarding PAR or its products or services. You can opt out of receiving these promotional communications at any time by following the instructions in the e-mail.

We may also use your e-mail address to contact you to verify and/or update any information related to services, features, or transactions that you have requested via our Web site, as well as to notify you of new product releases and/or software updates. Although you may opt out of the promotional e-mails as noted above, you should be aware that, as long as you use our products and services or otherwise maintain a business relationship with us, you may not opt out of receiving communications from us relating specifically to those products and services or that business relationship.

### "Contact Us" & "PAR Report Card" Pages

You may also provide Personally Identifiable Information to us when you voluntarily communicate with us, such as by requesting information via e-mail, utilizing the "Contact Us" or "PAR Report Card" or similar feedback features on the Web site, or otherwise contacting us electronically. We may retain such Personally Identifiable Information for use and disclosure consistent with this Privacy Policy.

### Change in Ownership or Business Transfers

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy assets. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets. Also, in the event that PAR or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information, including Personally Identifiable Information, will of course be one of the transferred assets to the extent permissible under law.

### Other Information

We collect additional information about how you use and access our Web site to analyze trends, administer our Web site, track users' navigation on the Site, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use, which enables us to improve the Site by making it more accessible and easier to navigate. For example, we may automatically receive and record information in our server logs from your browser, including your IP address (the Internet address of your PC), your computer's name, the type and version of your Web browser, referrer addresses, and other generally accepted log information. IP addresses are not linked to Personally Identifiable Information. We may also record page views (hit counts) and other general statistical and tracking information, which will be aggregated with that of other users in order to understand how our Web site is being used.

### Referrers

A "referrer" is the information passed along by a Web browser that references the Web URL you linked from and is automatically collected by our Web server. We may collect and use this information to understand the Web sites referring traffic to our Web site and to present appropriate content to our potential users. We may tabulate referrer information on an aggregate basis to identify trends and traffic patterns.

PAR may share aggregated demographic information with our partners. This is not linked to any personal information that identifies any individual person. PAR may use your profile information to create personalized content, offers, and services, but this information will be used only by PAR and its affiliates.

## Other Disclosure

PAR and its affiliates may disclose any or all of your Personally Identifiable Information if we are required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the law or comply with legal process served on us (for example, under a subpoena, court order, or other regulatory requirement or to maintain or protect the security of the Web site); (b) protect and/or defend our rights or property or other legal interests or of any Web site user; or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the safety of the public or other users of the Web site. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. If we receive legal process calling for the disclosure of any of your Personally Identifiable Information, we will attempt to notify you via the e-mail address you supplied during registration within a reasonable amount of time before we respond to the request, unless such notification is not permitted.

## Use of Third Parties or Agents by PAR

As noted earlier, PAR may employ third parties or other companies to perform functions on our behalf, such as processing and fulfilling online orders or requests, processing credit card payments, shipping or delivering packages, providing customer service, sending print and electronic mail, removing repetitive information from customer and e-mail lists, maintaining and analyzing information collected and/or stored via the Web site, hosting sites from this Web site, measuring the effectiveness of promotions and e-mails, performing analyses of users' activities on [www.parinc.com](http://www.parinc.com/), serving images via our Web site, and fulfilling other functions necessary to our business.

PAR also may use third party vendors or other companies to assist in providing certain services, products, and communications to you, such as delivering newsletters, magazines, alerts, and other communications to those Web site users who have opted in to receive them. In the event that we utilize third party vendors or companies to provide any of the services described above or similar services, we may need to share your Personally Identifiable Information with them to enable those companies to perform their obligations. However, we will provide these companies only with the information necessary to perform their functions on our behalf, and we will not authorize them to use your Personally Identifiable Information for any other purpose. In such event, these companies are required to agree, in writing, that they will abide by the privacy statement and privacy standards implemented herein, including the relevant confidentiality and security provisions.

## Security

PAR uses secure connections during the transmission of log in, registration, and membership information. This means that information collected through the pages dealing with sign in, registration, and membership information is encrypted before it is sent over the Internet between your computer and PAR computers. The technology used is called Transport Layer Security, version 1.2 (TSL 1.2). Through the use of this technology, the information collected through those pages is encrypted on your computer, sent through the Internet as encrypted code, and decoded on either PAR's secure server or the systems of the third party contracted to provide the service in question. You can verify that the connection is secure because you will see a key or a padlock (or other similar security symbol) at the bottom of your browser screen. Another identifier of a secure connection is the URL (or Web site address); the address will change from http://www4.parinc.com/ to http **s** ://www4.parinc.com/ or a similar page when a secure connection is in place.

Although we employ data encryption technology, you should be aware that there is an inherent risk in transmitting any data electronically. This risk is inherent in all Internet dealings. Consequently, we cannot guarantee that any Personally Identifiable Information transmitted will be prevented from being viewed or used by any particular person and, therefore, you agree to hold us harmless from and against any injury, financial or otherwise, that results from such unauthorized viewing or use. Moreover, e-mails sent to us over the Internet are susceptible to detection, decryption, eavesdropping, and/or tampering. Thus, you agree to hold us harmless from and against any harm, financial or otherwise, that results from such detection, decryption, eavesdropping, or tampering of e-mails.

In addition, you must take steps to maintain the security of your private information by keeping your password and other personal information confidential. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to log out of your account when you finish using a shared computer.

## Updating Your Information

PAR will always permit you to decline—or "opt–out of"—certain mailings and other materials we may offer. You may opt out of further communications at any time by following the instructions in the e-mails that you receive. In addition, if you request, we will remove your name and other Personally Identifiable Information from our active databases. Please understand, however, that it may be impossible to remove this information completely, due to backups and records of deletions. If you do not want to receive e-mail from us or to add or update certain personal information, you may contact us electronically by clicking here. As an alternative, you may write to us with your request at the following mailing address: PAR, Inc., 16204 N. Florida Ave., Lutz, Florida 33549. You will be removed from our databases generally within ten (10) business days of our receipt of your request. You may also request to review any Personally Identifiable Information that we maintain about you by sending a written request to the same address, subject to our verification of your identity.

## Links

Our Site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that PAR is not responsible for the privacy policies of other sites. We encourage our Web site users to be aware when they leave our Web site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects Personally Identifiable Information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to the information collected by our Web site.

## Questions About Our Privacy Policy

If you choose to visit our Web site, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions of Use, including limitations on damages and application of the law of the state of Florida. Please let us know if you have any questions about our Privacy Policy. Simply click here to contact us, or send an e-mail to Kay Cunningham at [kcunningham@parinc.com](mailto:kcunningham@parinc.com).
